# **Russell Chapman**

#### chpmnrssll@gmail.com

429 Navajo Ave, Simla CO (719) 541-5607

I've been programming for more than 20 years and have been involved in freelancing off and on since 2012. Real-time graphics, web application development, and open source often grab my attention. More info about me is available on my portfolio site, my upWork profile, or on GitHub @chpmnrssll

# **Skills**

- Content management systems (Netlify, CosmicJS, WordPress)
- JAMstack & static site generators (Jekyll, Nuxt, VuePress, Gatsby)
- Responsive design, lazy loading, SEO, optimization
- JavaScript, Node.js, PHP, Google Apps Script
- Vue.js, React, Backbone.js, jQuery, Express.js
- MongoDB, NoSQL, SQL, JSON, CSV, XML
- · Bower, Gulp, Grunt, NPM, Webpack
- HTML5, CSS3, BEM, Sass, Stylus
- DevOps, CI/CD, Docker, Linux, Bash, SSH, Git
- API, MVC, MV\*, PWA, REST, SPA, OOP
- Canvas, WebGL, SVG

# **Projects**

### WordPress to Jekyll conversion

09.2018 - 10.2018

Converted an existing WordPress/PHP site to a Jekyll static site while maintaining all theme elements and functionality. Makes use of the Jekyll Archives plugin.

Source: https://github.com/gwidgets/gwidgets.github.io/

Live: http://www.g-widgets.com/

#### **Multithreaded Downloader**

05.2018 - 07.2018

A browser-based multi-threaded downloader for Backblaze B2 implemented in vanilla JavaScript.

More info: <a href="https://chpmnrssll.github.io/vuepress/pages/portfolio/multithread/">https://chpmnrssll.github.io/vuepress/pages/portfolio/multithread/</a>

#### **Portfolio Site**

08.2017 - Current

My portfolio site is a single-page PWA hosted on GitHub Pages with both VuePress and Jekyll versions. You'll find more information about many other projects I've worked on under the "Development Portfolio" or "Development History" sections.

VuePress version: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/vuepress/

Jekyll version: <a href="https://chpmnrssll.github.io/jekyll/">https://chpmnrssll.github.io/jekyll/</a>

# **Experience**

## UpWork / oDesk - Full Stack Developer

2013 ~ present Worked with various clients (worldwide) as a contractor/freelance developer.

Detailed history and feedback is available on my upWork profile page:

https://www.upwork.com/fl/russellchapman

## Like Minds Design - PHP Developer

03.2013 – 07.2013 Developed custom WordPress plugin and integrated into Mississippi Court Reporters

Associations' new membership site: <a href="http://mscra.com/">http://mscra.com/</a>. More information about this project is available at: <a href="https://chpmnrssll.github.io/vuepress/pages/portfolio/mcra/">https://chpmnrssll.github.io/vuepress/pages/portfolio/mcra/</a>

## Freelance - Web Developer

1999 ~ 2013 Developed several websites ranging from static HTML to custom content management

systems in PHP. More info here: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/vuepress/pages/portfolio/

Other

2005 ~ 2010 ASE certified diesel mechanic, parts counter, and service writer at Travel Centers of

America in Limon, CO. Also contracted as on-call/emergency roadside service provider

in the Colorado Springs area.

# **Education**

# edX/BerkeleyX - Computer Science

2012

 CS169.1x: Software as a Service - SaaS, Ruby on Rails https://verify.edx.org/cert/5e306e9de87e4b699e30024caa925ff7

 CS188.1x: Artificial Intelligence - Machine Learning, Python https://verify.edx.org/cert/3e462d2a82e94c4da653c63924dbc56a

# Pikes Peak Community College - Computer Science

1997 ~ 2011

- DRT 283 Advanced Animation
- DRT 201 Intro to Computer Animation
- CSC 161 Computer Science II, C++
- CSC 160 Computer Science I, C++
- AST 102 Astronomy II \*
- AST 101 Astronomy I \*
- SPS 101 Spaceflight \*
- MAT 075 Pre-Algebra

<sup>\*</sup> NASA Scholorship program